<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text" xml:lang="en">Webworke.rs – Life and Craft in Columbus, OH</title><subtitle type="text">Webworke.rs is a website about folks who make websites in Columbus, OH.</subtitle><link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="http://webworke.rs/feed.xml"/><link href="http://webworke.rs/"/><id>http://webworke.rs/</id><icon>http://webworke.rs/favicon-196x196.png</icon><updated>2014-11-03T07:48:52Z</updated><author><name>David Ensinger</name><email>david@webworke.rs</email></author><rights type="text">Copyright © 2014 Webworke.rs. All rights reserved.</rights><entry><title type="text">Angie Meeker</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://webworke.rs/angie-meeker/" /><id>http://webworke.rs/angie-meeker</id><published>2014-11-01T12:03:00-04:00</published><updated>2014-11-01T12:03:00-04:00</updated><category term="digital-strategy" label="Digital Strategy"/><category term="marketing" label="Marketing"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ Angie Meeker is the Chief Strategy Officer at <a href="http://angiemeekerdesigns.com/">Angie Meeker Designs</a>, a boutique digital agency. She’s also the organizer of <a href="http://columbus.wordcamp.org/">WordCamp Columbus</a> and the co-organizer of the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/wp-columbus/">Columbus WordPress Meetup</a>. She works with her clients to help them increase awareness, efficiency, and revenue through internet marketing. ]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p class="lede"><span class="lede-location">Short North Coffee House &mdash;</span> Angie Meeker is the Chief Strategy Officer at <a href="http://angiemeekerdesigns.com/">Angie Meeker Designs</a>, a boutique digital agency. She’s also the organizer of <a href="http://columbus.wordcamp.org/">WordCamp Columbus</a> and the co-organizer of the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/wp-columbus/">Columbus WordPress Meetup</a>. She and her husband Robert work with their clients to increase their awareness, efficiency, and revenue through internet marketing.<p><p class="question"><strong>Tell me about Angie Meeker Designs. What do you do? Who’s your ideal client?</strong></p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> If you were to ask me five months ago, I would have said, “I’m a freelancer.” We’re only now starting to embrace the idea that we’re a boutique digital agency. Our business is to help other businesses increase their revenue, efficiency, and awareness through internet marketing, whether that’s via their website, email marketing or social media.</p><div class="media--right media--1-4 media--min-200"><picture><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-portrait-480by480-9e1697.jpg" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-portrait-320by320-9e1697.jpg"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-portrait-480by480-9e1697.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-portrait-320by320-9e1697.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-portrait-512by512-9e1697.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-portrait-479by479-9e1697.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-portrait-320by320-9e1697.jpg" alt="Photo of Angie Meeker" ></picture><div class="media-caption">Angie Meeker is the Chief Strategy Officer at <a href="http://angiemeekerdesigns.com/" class="media-link">Angie Meeker Designs</a>, a boutique digital agency.</div></div><p>As for our ideal client, we just started reading through <a href="http://www.bookyourselfsolid.com/">“Book Yourself Solid”</a> by Michael Port, which is a book that helps you decide who your ideal client is. A few days ago I would have said that our ideal client is any business or nonprofit that has good work to do and has the money to pay us, but that’s not really true. We have realized that the businesses we really want to be working with are ones that are in the travel industry. That would give us the opportunity to work with local businesses across the country. That feels like a really specific niche now that I say it, but that’s where we want to be heading.</p><p>Previously we’ve mostly worked with small business and nonprofits. Although in the past six months our clients have become larger and larger, which is where we are now.</p><p class="question"><strong>What are the services that you are most excited about providing?</strong></p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> I get most excited about helping our clients with their content marketing because that’s what drives the most traffic to their site. It also helps them build the best relationships with their customers.</p><p>When we first started, we were just selling websites. We said, “We’ll build it. Whatever you need, we’ll build it.” And we trusted the client to know what they needed, which wasn’t always in the client’s best interest. We’ve transitioned to asking, “What do you need this work to return for you?,” because there’s got to be a hard number that they’re working towards. It may be revenue or any other goal that can be measured. We want to report back to say, “Due to our work, we’ve returned back to you two or three times your investment with us based on these measurements.” That moves the discussion away from cost and towards the true value of our services.</p><p>We want to work with clients who are willing to tell us, “Here’s where our business is now and here’s where we want it to be. What strategies can we put in place to get us there?” Instead of just, “I think I need a website,” or, “I think I need to be active on social networks.” The content marketing is the primary goal and driver of value, while our WordPress development services are truthfully just a really great tool for sharing that information and reaching that goal.</p><blockquote class="quote quote-full"><p class="quote-text">The content marketing is the primary goal and driver of value, while our WordPress development services are truthfully just a really great tool for sharing that information and reaching that goal.</p></blockquote><p class="question"><strong>Ultimately you want to provide the services that help your clients achieve their goals, even if your clients mistake the means for the ends. You’re the expert, even though some clients may not always recognize that.</strong></p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> The difference between a client whose goal is only a website is that those people aren’t looking for an expert. They’ve already found the solution and it’s just a website, so they think that they’re good to go.</p><p>What we really want is someone who tells us their goals and asks, “How can you help us? What do you have to offer?” And those are the clients that we’re most willing to partner with and provide our services to. Dealing with clients who have already decided what they want, when they’re mistaken about it, are often very difficult to work with. We’ve had a few of those.</p><p class="question"><strong>So Bob recently joined full time? Quit his job and went all in with Angie Meeker Designs, right?</strong></p><p>Yes.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> I felt like he didn’t care for his job in the first place and it’s okay to say that. There were aspects of it that he liked and aspects that he didn’t.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> It’s fair to say that we made a judgement based on where I could make the most impact and money. I was in the position of working for a nonprofit and not being very well compensated for my work, so it wasn’t as difficult a decision as it might have been otherwise.</p><p>Angie and I had been discussing the future of the agency. She can of course keep doing what she’s been doing, but there’s a limit to what she can do herself. If we want to take the business further we need to analyze our processes, so that getting a client takes less time and working through a project becomes more efficient. Angie’s one person so she can’t necessarily give the one-on-one contact that some of our clients need.</p><p>One example of this is that Angie does the work, but when she’s busy it’s hard to communicate everything that’s being done to a client. So some clients get worried and frequently ask for updates, whether it’s a text, an email, or a phone call. Sometimes we even get all three over the course of a day. That makes it hard for her to focus on the task at hand, so we’re working on having systems in place to alleviate that.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> Bob’s background is in public administration and that’s what he’s spent his career doing. He not only helps our own business, but now assists our our clients with their processes in a way that’s different than most digital agencies are able to do. We’re now able to make that connection between the design, marketing, and the business operations, which is very exciting to me.</p><p class="question"><strong>Not only are your skill sets complimentary, but he also frees you up to do more of what you’re specialized in and like to do.</strong></p><p>Absolutely. We’re just getting into that. He’s been onboard since March, but honestly over the summer he spent most of his time with our daughter Nila, which is fantastic since it’s been a long time since he’s been able to spend that much time with her.</p><p>Now that school has started, we’re looking at our systems to make everything more efficient. For so long I’ve done everything: marketing, selling, designing, building, follow up, maintenance, all of it. If we’re going to grow we need to put systems in place so that some of the work can be passed off. The next project will probably be the first one where we actually hire a designer and a developer instead of having me do that work, which is a big deal for us as a company.</p><div class="media--left media--1-4 media--min-200"><a href="http://angiemeekerdesigns.com/marketing-business-using-wordpress/" class="media-image--link"><picture><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-wordpress-marketing-480by413-7ad825.jpg" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-wordpress-marketing-320by275-7ad825.jpg"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-wordpress-marketing-480by413-7ad825.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-wordpress-marketing-320by275-7ad825.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-wordpress-marketing-512by440-7ad825.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-wordpress-marketing-479by412-7ad825.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-wordpress-marketing-320by275-7ad825.jpg" alt="An image for Marketing Your Business Using WordPress" ></picture></a><div class="media-caption">One of Angie’s full day workshops, <a href="http://angiemeekerdesigns.com/marketing-business-using-wordpress/" class="media-link">Marketing Your Business Using WordPress</a>.</div></div><p class="question"><strong>How long have you been working as Angie Meeker Designs?</strong></p><p>I’ve been doing it since 2008, although in the past year and a half I can say, “Wow, this is a business,” instead of a very profitable hobby.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> The date I use is August, 2008.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> Yeah. That’s when we started. I don’t know why you said August.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> Because that’s an accurate date, that’s when you had your first job.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> I used to be a youth pastor and right after we got married we moved to Northern Iraq, in Kurdistan, where Bob was working. When we came back, I decided I didn’t want to work in the church anymore. So, I asked myself, “What skills do I have from working in the church?” I had some website skills that I learned on the job, of course looking back I’m embarrassed…</p><p class="question"><strong>Hey all of us have terrible websites in our past.</strong></p><p>So website work is what I started doing to make a little money. Our daughter was less than a year old, so I wanted to be home with her. At the time I thought, “I’ll just figure out how to advertise on Craigslist and I’ll get some clients that way.” And I did. The first site I did was for $200 and I thought that was a big deal! It was for a barbecue company that’s still around and they still have that same website, which does exactly what they need it to do, although perhaps I should approach them about a redesign soon.</p><p class="question"><strong>You’re a lot more skilled now, so I bet you could charge more than $200!</strong></p><p>Hopefully they would give me barbecue again too!</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> At first Angie did a lot of bartering for her work, so we got all sorts of cool stuff.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> We got catering and even a garden installed in our backyard, although we don’t do that anymore…</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> …unless somebody had something really good.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> It would need to be something really good because we don’t do that anymore. Anyway, that’s what we did. I’ve only ever used WordPress, which put us on the path that we’re on now. I went to <a href="http://columbus.wordcamp.org">WordCamp Columbus</a> in 2009 and thought, “Oh my gosh, look at all this cool stuff I can do.”</p><p class="question"><strong>So you’ve really grown a lot with WordPress.</strong></p><blockquote class="quote quote-small media--right media--1-4 media--min-200"><p class="quote-text">I went to WordCamp Columbus in 2009 and thought, “Oh my gosh, look at all this cool stuff I can do.</p></blockquote><p>I have, even though I’m not a developer. I still can’t build anything from scratch. You know what I mean? But I don’t have to.</p><p class="question"><strong>You don’t need to.</strong></p><p>Most clients don’t care if you can, at least not the clients that I work with. They don’t care that it’s WordPress or that it wasn’t hand coded. They only want to be able to update it themselves, with the confidence that it works and helps them reach their goals.</p><p class="question"><strong>How did you become involved with the WordPress meetups?</strong></p><p>I organized the 2011 WordCamp in Columbus after the previous organizers bowed out. I didn’t want it to go away because it had been so valuable to me. I had experience in event planning from my work with the church, so I volunteered to organize it and thought, “If it flops, so what?” At least I tried to keep it going. The previous year it wasn’t really focused on WordPress, so I wanted to fix that and keep it only about WordPress.</p><p><a href="http://wordpressfoundation.org/">The WordPress Foundation</a> would prefer that a city not have a WordCamp unless a local meetup already exists. Columbus didn’t have one, so we inadvertently did it backwards. After that first WordCamp we started the meetup and I’ve just kept doing it since then. It’s always been interesting since we have novices, developers, designers, and business owners who come. It’s really a diverse group, although we’re still working on making it welcoming and interesting to as many people as possible.</p><div class="media--left"><a href="http://columbus.wordcamp.org/" class="media-image--link"><picture><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-wordcamp-columbus-184by185-8632bc.png" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-wordcamp-columbus-184by185-8632bc.png"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-wordcamp-columbus-184by185-8632bc.png" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-wordcamp-columbus-184by185-8632bc.png" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-wordcamp-columbus-184by185-8632bc.png" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-wordcamp-columbus-184by185-8632bc.png" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-wordcamp-columbus-184by185-8632bc.png" alt="Screenshot of columbus.wordcamp.org" itemprop="contentURL" ></picture></a><div class="media-caption">The logo for last year’s <a href="http://columbus.wordcamp.org/" class="media-link">WordCamp Columbus</a>.</div></div><p>Also, back to WordCamp, the past couple years it’s just been Bob and me, although <a href="https://twitter.com/arcware">Dave</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/jonathandavis">John</a> helped one year too. This was the first year that I had to find speakers for both days of camp. It’s a risk to the event if I’m the only one organizing it, so after this year, I asked for help from the Foundation to help cover roles and organize speakers. People responded overwhelmingly well to it, so I now have help so that I’m not trying to doing everything.</p><p class="question"><strong>It must be a lot of work to organize and run a WordCamp.</strong></p><p>It will be better next year than what it was this year because it’s got all these great people involved with it, who are excited about it. WordCamp is one of my favorite things that I do, so I am looking forward to it.</p><p class="question"><strong>Tell me about <a href="http://yourcrimesite.com/">Your Crime Site</a>.</strong></p><p>One of our clients is the <a href="http://stopcrime.org/">Central Ohio Crime Stoppers</a>, for whom we developed a website several years ago. After their site debuted they started to get phone calls from other Crime Stopper organizations that wanted a similar site. This was right after I learned about WordPress Multisite, which was exactly what I needed to start spinning off websites.</p><p>Basically, we host the crime sites and ensure that they’re kept up-to-date. Either the client manages their content or we add and update it for them, for a fee. We also offer event registration and management options.</p><p>Our one big feature that distinguishes us from other competitors in the crime site space is that we put every crime on its own page, so it can have a unique URL. It’s much easier for visitors to search the site and pass around the links, which helps with the ultimate goal of showcasing the faces of the criminals, so they can be captured.</p><p>It’s a nice side project, although we go back and forth between wanting to focus on it and wanting to kill it.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> What’s funny is that one of us will say, “I think it’s time we need to find someone else to manage this.” And then we’ll change our minds and say, “No, look at all potential it has!” And then time will pass and the other person will say, “I think we’re done here,” but by then the other one of us will reply, “No, there’s still more opportunity!”</p><p>It has a lot of potential for Crime Stoppers and for us.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> It has. It’s something that we don’t take advantage of.</p><div class="media--right media--1-4 media--min-250"><a href="http://yourcrimesite.com/" class="media-image--link"><picture><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-screenshot-your-crime-site-480by374-b1919c.jpg" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-screenshot-your-crime-site-320by249-b1919c.jpg"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-screenshot-your-crime-site-480by374-b1919c.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-screenshot-your-crime-site-320by249-b1919c.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-screenshot-your-crime-site-719by560-b1919c.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-screenshot-your-crime-site-479by373-b1919c.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-screenshot-your-crime-site-320by249-b1919c.jpg" alt="Screenshot of YourCrimeSite.com" itemprop="contentURL" ></picture></a><div class="media-caption">The website for <a href="http://yourcrimesite.com/" class="media-link">Your Crime Site</a>.</div></div><p class="question"><strong>So it comes down to what’s the best use of your time? That’s probably constantly in </strong>your thoughts.</p><p>It is, yeah. The thing about Your Crime Site is that it’s this whole little ecosystem that would allow me to do all the things that I really like to do. I like teaching, so it’s an opportunity for me to help this entire little niche to learn how they can better market themselves online. But at the same time, it doesn’t yet meet all the criteria of what we really want to do. We haven’t killed it yet because it’s still doing what it needs to do for the couple of organizations that have it. It’ll stick around for a while more, I think.</p><p class="question"><strong>Cool. What’s the Eight Hour Business Makeover?</strong></p><p>Unfortunately that’s a project that’s been killed. I think it’s a really great idea and I had good feedback for it, but it’s just not a good fit for the businesses that would actually need the lessons contained within it. It was meant to be was an introduction to the pillars of internet marketing, to see how each area is connected. The participants would receive a workbook with exercises so that they could begin executing in each area of study. The problem was that the work involved would require more time, and assistance, than could be fit into a one or two day conference.</p><p>I’ve thought about making it an online course, so that it’s not crammed into such a short period of time. But the businesses that I’ve worked with don’t yet understand how to use those, or aren’t willing to do the work to put themselves through each one of those areas. So I decided the course work isn’t a good match for the client. I let the domain expire, although killing a project doesn’t mean that you can’t come back to it. </p><p class="question"><strong>Tell me about the Freelancers Conference.</strong></p><p>I’m always learning new things from running my business, which I make sure to share with others. As a result, I often have people coming up to me who ask, “When are you going to do a conference that helps us learn everything you know about contracts, onboarding, pricing, or even how to pick clients?” It has happened enough times that I finally decided that we’re going to do it.</p><p>So, next March we’re going to put on the Freelancers Conference, which will be focused on all the aforementioned topics and more. It won’t be specific to the WordPress community, since all sorts of small business people need to learn how to position themselves in their respective markets. We’ve asked the community what they want to learn about and now we’re finding the best speakers to cover those topics. I’m really excited about it. It will be a nonprofit event, the tickets will be affordable, and it will be held over two days.</p><p>I’m telling the speakers, “Don’t just bring an inspirational message about pricing or some talk about how you grew your team.” I want them to bring something more practical, something that our attendees can leave with, which will help them take the next step in their careers. It will be almost a workshop since it will be so hands-on. As soon as I mentioned it, I had people saying, “Let me know if I can help. I want to come speak. I’ll bring my team in to help.”</p><div class="media--left media--1-4 media--min-250"><a href="http://angiemeekerdesigns.com/" class="media-image--link"><picture><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-screenshot-angie-meeker-designs-480by374-976d12.jpg" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-screenshot-angie-meeker-designs-320by249-976d12.jpg"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-screenshot-angie-meeker-designs-480by374-976d12.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-screenshot-angie-meeker-designs-320by249-976d12.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-screenshot-angie-meeker-designs-719by560-976d12.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-screenshot-angie-meeker-designs-479by373-976d12.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-screenshot-angie-meeker-designs-320by249-976d12.jpg" alt="Screenshot of AngieMeekerDesigns.com" itemprop="contentURL" ></picture></a><div class="media-caption">The website for <a href="http://angiemeekerdesigns.com/" class="media-link">Angie Meeker Designs</a>.</div></div><p class="question"><strong>What’s a typical work day for you?</strong></p><p>We get up and take our daughter to school, so we don’t get back from that until about 9:30 AM. After that we start our work day. We don’t have a particular structure to our day, but we work until 2:30 to 3:00 PM and then we pick Nila up. And then I try really hard to stop working until she goes to bed, which is around 8:00 PM. In the past we would go pick Nila up from school and then I would go straight back to work until dinner, after which we would put her to bed and I’d still be working. It was just awful.</p><p class="question"><strong>So you’re trying for a better work and life balance?</strong></p><p>Exactly that. From 9:30 AM until 3:00 PM is not a very long time. A lot of freelancers think, “Oh, I’m going to work 40 hours a week for myself,” but that’s not true, at least in billable hours. The reality is that you probably have about 20 hours of the week when you’re doing work that directly relates to a client project. We’ve obviously moved away from this, but work that I could bill a client for, instead of work where I’m researching or doing administration. As we’ve learned to price our work better, it’s freed up a little bit of time.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> Yeah we don’t have typical work days. Angie works every day from when Nila leaves for school, until she gets back home. Once Nila goes to bed, Angie is often back working.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> Not every night.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> But when you do it’s until 10:00 PM. And then there’s weekends…</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> No, I don’t work through the weekends anymore.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> Yes, you do.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> No, I don’t.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> Yes.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> No.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> Yes.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> Yeah, but I’m trying not to do that anymore. On Tuesday afternoon we go to Nila’s school and do a reading group because the kids really need the help. If anyone reading this wants to help, let us know.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> If you’re out there, reading this.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> On Friday at noon I meet with a group of folks online for a business mastermind. That’s really the only structure to our week at this point.</p><p class="question"><strong>Do you work at home?</strong></p><p>Sometimes if I really need to get work done, I’ll go somewhere else, but mostly I just work at home. Bob has an office upstairs and I have one downstairs. I know there are benefits to coworking, but at the same time I don’t want to spend the money on the space. Even if we were a small agency, I wouldn’t want us to move into a space. Instead I’d want us to be working online, from wherever we wanted to work. It’s just us, so we work from home.</p><p class="question"><strong>How do you spend your free time?</strong></p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> We spend it with Nila.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> Yeah, although unfortunately my one hobby has become binge watching television, when I’m not with Nila or doing work.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> He does, not me. I’m trying to introduce Nila to things that she otherwise wouldn’t be introduced to. Like going fishing.</p><p class="question"><strong>How’d that go? I saw your tweet about that.</strong></p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> It was fun. We fell in the river.</p><p class="question"><strong>Which river?</strong></p><p>The Scioto.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> So, not me. Bob and Nila.</p><p class="question"><strong>You’re here now, which is good.</strong></p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> Right. We survived.</p><p class="question"><strong>You didn’t drift down into the Ohio.</strong></p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> I was on the dock and they were on the ramp, which was covered in algae. Nila slipped and then Bob slipped, so I then turn around and they’re both yelling, “We’re gonna die!” They didn’t, but for a moment they really had me. They couldn’t stand up for awhile because it was so slippery.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> I would like to say two things. One, I never wanted to go to the boat dock in the first place. I said it was a bad idea.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> He did.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> And I tried everything to get us to go somewhere else. Secondly, we had been playing and Nila slid in and couldn’t get out because it was so slick. Angie thinks it’s funny because she didn’t see Nila’s face when she realized that she couldn’t get up, so she was sliding into the river. I had to grab her. I knew that I could swim and I’d be fine, but I also realized that I couldn’t stand up either because it was too slippery. This all happened in the space of several seconds. Angie thinks it’s funny because she wasn’t traumatized like I was.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> Well, also, Bob’s a city kid. So it was humorous to me. He didn’t want to go in the first place, but we went and then he falls in the river. It was funny. Sort of.</p><div class="media--right media--1-4 media--min-200"><picture><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-family-480by480-c4ad9b.jpg" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-family-320by320-c4ad9b.jpg"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-family-480by480-c4ad9b.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-family-320by320-c4ad9b.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-family-626by626-c4ad9b.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-family-479by479-c4ad9b.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/03-angie-meeker-family-320by320-c4ad9b.jpg" alt="Photo of work and life balance" ></picture><div class="media-caption">Work and life balance for the Meekers.</div></div><p class="question"><strong>Did you catch any fish?</strong></p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> No.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> Yeah, we went in the late afternoon and our side of the river was too sunny. All the fish were on the other side. Nila still had fun, which was the point.</p><p>Most weekends we’re doing something together because we’re really strict about her bedtime. I know it sounds weird in response to this question. We’ve always put her to bed around 7:30 PM, which is early, so by the time we’re done with homework, make dinner, and put her to bed, the night’s over.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> And neither one of us is very crafty to take up a craft.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> In this part you can just write, “boring.” Anyway... </p><p class="question"><strong>What about your goals for the remainder of this year?</strong></p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> My goal is to have another $35,000 in revenue before the end of this year. A less tangible goal is to position ourselves so that next year we’re able to work with more of our ideal clients. This represents a huge shift in how we’re marketing ourselves, so we need to figure out how to reach these businesses. The other goal of mine is to really knock the Freelancers Conference out of the park because I’d like to do more events like that.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> My goal is to have all our new systems identified, mapped out, and working, which I don’t think will take until the end of the year.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> I think it will.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> It might.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> I haven’t needed that sort of stuff yet, but we need to get them in place or we won’t be able to grow beyond where we are right now.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> I want a client from the Caribbean by the end of the year.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> There you go, go do it, Bob.</p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> That’s what we call a goal.</p><p class="question"><strong>You never know, right?</strong></p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> If we can get to one of the French speaking islands in the Caribbean, then we can bring Nila, since she’s learning French at school. We’ll go for practice, so it’s not just for my own enjoyment.</p><p>All you need is one client. Do a good job and then with word of mouth referrals...</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> Yeah that’s true. I had someone email me a couple months ago and ask me the ways that I’ve advertised our business. And I responded that we hadn’t done any advertising at all. </p><p class="question"><strong>That speaks really well for the work you do.</strong></p><p><strong>Bob:</strong> I think so.</p><p><strong>Angie:</strong> I hope so. We have to stop before we say something silly.</p><br><hr><p>You’ve just read about <strong><a href="http://webworke.rs/angie-meeker/">Angie Meeker</a></strong> on <strong><a href="http://webworke.rs/">Webworke.rs</a></strong>, a website about folks who make websites in Columbus, OH.</p><p>For updates, follow us on <strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/Webworkers614">Facebook</a></strong>, <strong><a href="https://plus.google.com/+Webworkers614/">Google+</a></strong>, <strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/webworkers">LinkedIn</a></strong>, <strong><a href="http://Webworkers614.tumblr.com">Tumblr</a></strong>, and <strong><a href="http://twitter.com/Webworkers614">Twitter</a></strong>.</p>
 ]]></content></entry><entry><title type="text">Adam Schweigert</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://webworke.rs/adam-schweigert/" /><id>http://webworke.rs/adam-schweigert</id><published>2014-09-07T11:01:00-04:00</published><updated>2014-09-07T11:01:00-04:00</updated><category term="development" label="Development"/><category term="digital-strategy" label="Digital Strategy"/><category term="marketing" label="Marketing"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ Adam Schweigert works at the intersection of nonprofits, journalism, and technology as the Senior Director of Product &amp; Technology at <a href="http://investigativenewsnetwork.org/">Investigative News Network</a>. He’s also the founder of <a href="http://mediatoybox.com/">Media Toybox</a>, a digital consultancy that helps news and media companies win the internet. When he’s not developing for <a href="http://largoproject.org/">Project Largo</a>, a fully-featured WordPress theme for news websites, he can otherwise be found cycling, running, or gardening. ]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p class="lede"><span class="lede-location">Clintonville Cup o' Joe &mdash;</span> Adam Schweigert works at the intersection of nonprofits, journalism, and technology as the Senior Director of Product &amp; Technology at <a href="http://investigativenewsnetwork.org/">Investigative News Network</a>. He’s also the founder of <a href="http://mediatoybox.com/">Media Toybox</a>, a digital consultancy that helps news and media companies win the internet. When he’s not developing for <a href="http://largoproject.org/">Project Largo</a>, he can otherwise be found cycling, running, or gardening.<p><p class="question"><strong>What’s the mission of the Investigative News Network and the benefit to members to join?</strong></p><p>So the <a href="http://investigativenewsnetwork.org/">Investigative News Network (INN)</a> was founded in 2009 as an organization to support the growing ecosystem of nonprofit news in the US. The goal was to form a sort of trade association that would provide things like back office support (things like getting better deals on health insurance) and to help support editorial projects and enable members to collaborate better.</p><div class="media--right media--1-4 media--min-200"><picture><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-portrait-480by480-39118a.jpg" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-portrait-320by320-39118a.jpg"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-portrait-480by480-39118a.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-portrait-320by320-39118a.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-portrait-500by500-39118a.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-portrait-479by479-39118a.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-portrait-320by320-39118a.jpg" alt="Photo of Adam Schweigert" ></picture><div class="media-caption">Adam Schweigert is Senior Director of Product &amp; Technology at <a href="http://investigativenewsnetwork.org/" class="media-link">Investigative News Network</a>.</div></div><p>At the time there were around twenty members, but now it’s up to around one hundred. In addition to the back office services, we now provide technology services and also do a lot of training, mostly focused on basic business skills. A lot of people who start nonprofits often come from a journalism background and may not have as much of a background in business, technology, and all of the associated skills you need to run an effective news organization.</p><p>So we try to fill in those gaps, and especially technology-wise, which is my role, to look at the things that we can do to support the entire network. Things that make sense at that larger scale, such as building our Largo WordPress platform, finding deals on software, and developing tools that will be widely applicable. It would cost a fortune for each member to build their own tools and start from scratch to develop a website, but we can build once and then help everyone to use and adapt the tools we build.</p><p>So that’s why building <a href="http://largoproject.org/">Project Largo</a>, our WordPress framework, makes a lot of sense. Rather than having every single member start from scratch with a different CMS, a unique theme, and separate hosting, we bundle those things to save our members time and money. Especially for things like hosting, it’s much more effective for us to pay for high end hosting for the entire network than for everyone to purchase that on their own.</p><p>The members can instead spend the money they save on that last ten percent of stuff that’s unique to their organization. It allows them more flexibility to actually innovate, rather than on simply getting to the starting line. We always tell members that,“We’ll host your site, give you a framework to customize, and provide training and support, but that doesn’t mean that you shouldn’t invest the money you save by spending it on other things.”</p><blockquote class="quote quote-small media--left media--1-4 media--min-200"><p class="quote-text">The Investigative News Network helps nonprofit news organizations produce and distribute stories with impact, achieve cost efficiencies by pooling resources and develop new revenue streams to become sustainable businesses.</p><cite class="citation-small"><a href="http://investigativenewsnetwork.org/about/" class="citation-small--link">About INN</a></cite></blockquote><p>Even though there’s a cost savings, I would rather see our members reinvest their savings to experiment, to learn more about what’s most effective for their audience, because INN’s members are not monolithic. There’s a good diversity of sizes and focuses, so we can’t make a framework that would be the ideal solution for every member. I’d rather they spend the money they save on custom add-ons, design, and experimenting with different content approaches to see what’s most effective for them.</p><p class="question"><strong>How many staff members make up INN? How many on the technology side?</strong></p><p>The staff is up to eight or nine employees and then we have various consultants, contractors, interns, and other vendors. The tech team as of May was only me and a number of outside contractors, but we’re now building <a href="http://nerds.investigativenewsnetwork.org/">a team inside INN</a> because it makes more sense with the projects we have.</p><p>We were having a hard time finding contractors who had the same long term vision that we do. There’s also a lot of ongoing support requests from our members to customize or build additional functionality for our Largo framework. As an in-house product team, we’re just going to know the members and the framework so much better, so we’ll be able to do the work faster and cheaper.</p><p>As long as we have the demand and funding, I’m pretty keen on bringing more of that work back in-house. We’re now two people and will be adding a third soon, probably in the next couple of weeks. We still have some outside contractors and usually an intern or two.</p><p>We’re focused on growing the team by building upon a co-op model, where if members need support or custom work, we’ll do it for them, much like a small agency would. The members will pay us a very reasonable, subsidized rate to do the work, and we’ll use that money to offset some of our costs. This will then allow us to scale in an organic way to best address member needs as they change and evolve.</p><p class="question"><strong>What’s the size and composition of your ideal team?</strong></p><p>There’s only so big a size that would make sense for us. I think a team of five or six, at least as the core team may be ideal for building something like Largo. A team of five or six is fine and is probably as large as you would actually want to avoid becoming too big and having all the associated problems that come along with that.</p><p>I don’t think we’ll ever be a giant team, but we’ll probably continue to grow as INN’s membership grows. But there are only going to be so many nonprofit news organizations in the U.S., so there’s a ceiling to our growth. There’s also only so much money coming into the sector, even as our members become more financially stable, so that’s another potential limiting factor.</p><p class="question"><strong>Where does funding come from for INN?</strong></p><p>Today, INN is almost entirely funded by foundations, so we get grants, and some of those are for general operating expenses that aren’t restricted to any project, so we have some leeway in how we spend that. But some grants are focused on a particular project.</p><p>We’re now looking to diversify our revenue streams with things like our paid consulting program so that we’re less reliant on the foundation money. Fortunately, INN has really identified a need that a lot of foundations buy into, but at the same time foundations can change their priorities. Our funding has actually been pretty good and we’re funded by some of the larger, more stable foundations, which is great, but it still never hurts to have diversity in our revenue streams.</p><p class="question"><strong>Have you officially started the co-op model? What’s been the reaction from the members. Is this a hard sell?</strong></p><p>No, it’s actually been a really easy sell. We just announced it a month ago and this was after talking to a number of members. I make my decisions by listening to our membership and understanding what their unmet needs are. A lot of members are small enough that they don’t have a full time technology person on their staff, so they often hire contractors to fill in the gaps.</p><div class="media--right media--1-4 media--min-200"><a href="http://wisconsinwatch.org/" class="media-image--link"><picture><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-screenshot-wisconsin-watch-480by374-81d2ed.jpg" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-screenshot-wisconsin-watch-320by249-81d2ed.jpg"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-screenshot-wisconsin-watch-480by374-81d2ed.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-screenshot-wisconsin-watch-320by249-81d2ed.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-screenshot-wisconsin-watch-719by560-81d2ed.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-screenshot-wisconsin-watch-479by373-81d2ed.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-screenshot-wisconsin-watch-320by249-81d2ed.jpg" alt="Screenshot of WisconsinWatch.org" itemprop="contentURL" ></picture></a><div class="media-caption">The website for <a href="http://wisconsinwatch.org/" class="media-link">Wisconsin Center for Investigative Journalism</a>.</div></div><p>They fall into the same problem we’ve fallen into from time to time, where contractors aren’t necessarily well-aligned with their mission. The organizations lurch from project to project and don’t have that continuity in vision between their projects. The members also pay market rates for freelance technology help, which is often pretty expensive for a non-profit.</p><p>I approached them and asked, “What if we had a team that you could hire to do that development or support work, at a reduced rate, at least until you’re able to hire a full-time person?” There were enough members who thought that was a great idea that would be super helpful for them. So we’re figuring out how to make that happen.</p><p>There are also a lot of nonprofits that still don’t understand why it’s unreasonable to expect to pay a developer $30,000 a year. They might be able to find a really nice person right out of school, someone who would be willing to spend a couple of years working for them, or it’s someone who’s already made their money, right? [laughing]</p><p>But if you’re looking to pay a competitive salary and recruit top talent then that’s a lot harder to do. That’s something that INN is lucky to be able to do. If I can subsidize that cost with a little bit of foundation money, that’s why we can charge members around $50 an hour, which is very affordable for the quality of work you’ll get.</p><p class="question"><strong>One of the tools that you provide to your members is the Project Largo, which is what?</strong></p><p>It’s a <a href="http://wordpress.org">WordPress</a> framework, which is composed of an open source parent theme with associated plugins, that you can further customize. We’re aiming to give members basically a website in a box.</p><p>We build on all of the great things that WordPress is known for, particularly ease of use, so you can activate the theme, do the initial configuration, and in an hour you have a running website. The theme itself is built on a solid codebase that follows best practices. There’s metadata that’s associated with the content, which handles a lot of SEO and social media issues without adding additional plugins. For members we also host many of the sites, so we cover the cost of high end hosting, which includes all the security, performance optimization, and software updates. It’s a platform for members and an open source project too, so you can take it and modify it however you choose.</p><p class="question"><strong>Do you have any member organizations that use the framework to its full potential?</strong></p><p>[laughing] This is always a tough question. I think we’re getting there. There’s a lot we have a lot to do in regards to training and support to help organizations understand everything that’s available because there’s a lot of stuff that’s still not as obvious as I’d like it to be.</p><div class="media--left media--1-4 media--min-200"><a href="http://largoproject.org/" class="media-image--link"><picture><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-largo-project-logo-480by480-12395a.png" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-largo-project-logo-320by320-12395a.png"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-largo-project-logo-480by480-12395a.png" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-largo-project-logo-320by320-12395a.png" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-largo-project-logo-719by719-12395a.png" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-largo-project-logo-479by479-12395a.png" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-largo-project-logo-320by320-12395a.png" alt="Logo for Project Largo" itemprop="contentURL" ></picture></a><div class="media-caption">The logo for <a href="http://largoproject.org/" class="media-link">Project Largo</a> by <a href="http://alliberry.com/">Alli Berry</a>.</div></div><p>For instance, we encourage authors to fill in their profiles. If they link to their Twitter account or to a Google+ profile, it automatically inserts all the authorship markup and associated metadata. We don’t make that a requirement, so we need to do a better job of explaining why it’s important to do so.</p><p>WordPress has a lot of optional stuff, like descriptions for categories, which can provide a lot of context on a category landing page. No one ever uses that, though. There’s also the proper use of metadata, so having categories, tags, and using them effectively. It’s so obvious to us, what should be a category versus a tag, but it’s not always clear to our authors. “I’ll just make a bunch of categories,” which is very common.</p><p>We need to do more training, like “Here’s the best way to…” There’s a lot of special styling available for elements within a story, but too often an author needs to know the exact markup for it to display correctly. We need to document that stuff, which will be one of the first tasks for the designer that we’re now hiring.</p><p>There aren’t any sites that I would point to as being great examples, but that’s totally my fault, it’s not their fault. There are a lot of sites that do the fundamentals pretty well, but there’s no one really maximizing that and that’s just something that we have to focus a little more on. Although there are sites that are doing some awesome stuff too.</p><p class="question"><strong>Do you take feature requests from organizations?</strong></p><p>We do, but we try to apply a filter to their requests. Even if it’s a good idea, not everything can be a priority, just because we may have more pressing responsibilities. If there’s something that someone identifies that a lot of members would find of value and we can ship it in a couple of hours, we’ll often just build it. But if it’s a feature that might take a little more time, thought, and care, we’ll add it to the backlog and the next version of the framework might include it.</p><p>For more one-off requests, when members say, “I want to be able to do this one very specific thing,” that in my estimation other members are unlikely to want, and it’s very narrow, then those are the types of things we’re now helping to implement with our paid consulting program.</p><p>We’ve thought about having a place where a member could submit these requests and filter them up and down to help us gauge interest and I expect that’s something we’ll do soon. For future versions of the framework, now that we’ve gotten most of the fundamental stuff out of the way, we’ll prioritize more based on feedback from our members.</p><p class="question"><strong>So I was reading your Twitter feed…</strong></p><p>Oh God…</p><p class="question"><strong>Hey I feel like you make the most of the format!</strong></p><p>[laughs]</p><p class="question"><strong>In a recent tweet you wrote that people will need to pay for their news. What does the future of journalism look like, both for your average reader and for news organizations?</strong></p><p>So that’s a big question. As far as revenue goes, the model in the 20th century was essentially, “We’ll sell ads in this newspaper, it will show up on your doorstep every morning, and you’re guaranteed delivery of those ads.” An advertiser would pay a premium to reach that audience, although whether or not the audience actually looked at the ads is questionable, even though the ads appeared intermingled with the content.</p><blockquote class="quote quote-full"><p class="quote-text">Folks, I hate to break this to you. But to fix the media you're all just going to have to pay for news. Sorry, just how it has to be.</p><cite class="citation-small">Adam Schweigert (<a href="https://twitter.com/aschweig/status/499014560464916481" class="citation-small--link">@aschweig</a>)</cite></blockquote><p>There would usually be multiple newspapers in a town and they would have different perspectives, so you could, for example, buy ads to display to a particular, partisan audience. That was basically all there was, so the newspapers would charge a premium to deliver those ads in an effective and reliable way. The ads were expensive and composed a majority of the income for the newspaper, which used the money to hire lots of staff and things were great. Subscription fees were only a fraction of the total revenue, which no longer works for a variety of reasons.</p><p>Today there’s much more diversity in media, especially online. Unfortunately for advertisers, banner ads are not effective. Everyone who’s ever seen one knows that you only click on them by accident. There’s a certain branding value to them, which is why luxury goods companies still pay for them, but otherwise they’re not effective. As a result, ad rates have dropped and are now approaching zero. It’s great for companies buying advertising, but terrible for the publishers, who are now trying to figure out how to make money. This is why advertising has becoming increasingly desperate, online and in print. It’s a race to the bottom to find the next advertising technique that’s even more disruptive to the reader, in order to charge more, all the while rates continue to slide off a cliff.</p><p>Instead, we need to diversify our revenue streams. There are a lot of organizations that are now looking at ads as a piece of the pie, but they also organize events or sell premium content, for example. A revenue model for a nonprofit would also include foundation grants and individual donations. With this new model it’s much less likely that any one source of revenue will ever pay for the entire cost of producing serious news. If you want serious accountability journalism, in my opinion, there’s just no way out of consumers having to pay for it.</p><blockquote class="quote quote-small media--left media--1-4 media--min-200"><p class="quote-text">If you just expect to get your news for free as a result of advertisements, then you’re going to get what advertisers are going to pay for, which is editorially bankrupt journalism.</p></blockquote><p>If you just expect to get your news for free as a result of advertisements, then you’re going to get what advertisers are going to pay for, which is editorially bankrupt journalism. Some publications sell branded content, which is a slightly different story, but it’s still predicated on deception. It’s making the ads look enough like content in order to fool someone into accidentally reading it.</p><p>It’s an especially dangerous proposition for prestige brands, like The New York Times, because they risk diluting their brand by confusing consumers. The long term cost is an erosion of trust and that’s just not worth the money. At the moment you can get pretty good money for native advertising, but like other advertising, those rates are going to eventually continue to erode. I would rather see more organizations bite the bullet and just start charging for content than see them going down this slippery slope of blurring the lines between editorial and branded content.</p><p class="question"><strong>Where do you get your news from?</strong></p><p>All over the place. I get a lot of news from my Twitter feed and I always try to diversify the people I follow, so that I get perspectives outside of the media bubble. I’m actually pretty old, in internet terms anyway, so I have an RSS feed reader and still get news from that. I also subscribe to the Sunday New York Times, just because I enjoy drinking coffee and reading it, even though I’ve already read most of it by the time I get it! [laughs] I still enjoy that experience of reading it even though it’s probably, I don’t know what it is now, eight dollars an issue.</p><p class="question"><strong>Well, you get what you pay for.</strong></p><p>It’s more for the experience than the content that’s contained within it. I also listen to a lot of podcasts, a lot of public radio, and then obviously read content from INN member organizations. I can’t read it all, but I do try to share articles from there to give them a boost.</p><p class="question"><strong>Have you interacted with any of your favorite brands lately?</strong></p><p>[Laughing] My favorite brands? I just had an interaction with Charmin on Twitter. They were running a sponsored tweet, which didn’t make any sense, so I made a poop joke because that’s what Charmin does. That was my interaction with them. The way brands are using Twitter has gotten to be a little bit…</p><p class="question"><strong>Is there value in it? To them? Or for you?</strong></p><p>If it’s done well it can be very funny, but I don’t know that it’s effective, except in terms of awareness. The effectiveness of social media is a very similar question to the effectiveness of advertising in general, right? What are the goals? It’s become a requirement for customer service, but does it drive sales? I’m not convinced. We’re still in the early days of sponsored tweets, but the stuff I see tends to be from big national brands that I don’t buy anyway, so it hasn’t changed my behavior.</p><p>Right now it’s mostly jokes and the social media managers that run these accounts are so hardened, just because they need to be, I’m sure. Joking around with them is fun, knowing that there’s a person behind it who probably has a pretty good sense of humor. Certainly, it’s still a great way to get a brand’s attention if you have a bad experience. In my previous consulting life, a sort of gospel that I preached was that social media is more of a listening platform than a way to push a message, which just isn’t that effective in my opinion.</p><p class="question"><strong>So speaking of your previous life as a consultant, how’d you get into this line of work, what brought you to where you are now?</strong></p><p>It’s a long story. I double majored in music and biochemistry because I thought I was going to be a doctor, but I was paying for it with a music scholarship as an oboe player. After two years I ended up dropping biochem because juggling both majors was crazy without having any overlap between them.</p><p>So I spent five years and majored in oboe performance, music theory and music composition. But a music degree by itself is pretty much worthless, so of course I went to grad school. I went to <a href="http://www.iub.edu/">Indiana University</a>, which is a fantastic music school, to study composition, and added more of a computer music focus.</p><p>In grad school I got a part time job at <a href="http://indianapublicmedia.org/radio/">a public radio station</a>, where I started as a writer and producer. They eventually brought me on full time as the music director. I was probably the youngest classical music director in the history of public radio. It’s unusual because classical music is difficult to program. It’s not like pop songs, where you just play those same 40 songs. There is a thousand years of music and you need to assemble it in a way that flows well, yet is varied enough to still be interesting for both a more discerning audience and as background music for a typical dentist’s office.</p><p>After doing that for a couple years I was the person in the office who discovered podcasting. I told my co-workers that, “We should be doing this, this is the future.” We should be producing audio for the internet, not just putting our live stream online, so I started working more on the web at that point.</p><p>When I got that first full-time job I also decided to drop out of grad school, so I don’t have an actual master’s degree, which is kind of sad because I was pretty close and, particularly, because I had taken out a lot of student loans. I realized that I was not really into what I was doing. I was writing a lot of music that was esoteric enough that it was not really listenable, but was written more for winning awards.</p><div class="media--right media--1-4 media--min-200"><a href="http://kinseyconfidential.org/" class="media-image--link"><picture><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-screenshot-kinsey-confidential-480by374-db3280.jpg" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-screenshot-kinsey-confidential-320by249-db3280.jpg"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-screenshot-kinsey-confidential-480by374-db3280.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-screenshot-kinsey-confidential-320by249-db3280.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-screenshot-kinsey-confidential-719by560-db3280.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-screenshot-kinsey-confidential-479by373-db3280.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-screenshot-kinsey-confidential-320by249-db3280.jpg" alt="Screenshot of KinseyConfidential.org" itemprop="contentURL" ></picture></a><div class="media-caption">The website for <a href="http://kinseyconfidential.org/" class="media-link">Kinsey Confidential</a>.</div></div><p>But I realized the skills that I had were translatable into doing other stuff. So in my role at the public radio station, I transitioned into being responsible for the website, as well as doing online content development. What was interesting to me, is that the radio station roughly covers the southern half of Indiana. On air, they reach about 40,000 people, but I don’t recall if that’s a week or month, it’s fairly small and Bloomington is a pretty small town. They have a geographically limited audience, but being in a college town that has a very rich cultural life and associations with the university, there is a lot of strength and possibility for building content partnerships.</p><p>So my strategy was to look for projects that we could develop for a national audience, which was a great success. We launched probably a dozen different blogs and podcasts that were often very topically focused on a particular strength of a partner organization, whether it be an academic department or the Kinsey Institute, which was one of our biggest successes. <a href="http://kinseyconfidential.org/">Kinsey Confidential</a> was a podcast about sexual health, where we had the opportunity to give, essentially, sex advice with a real solid research footing. It was probably the raciest thing public radio has ever touched, so I am very proud of that.</p><p>We also had a partnership with a local chef, <a href="http://indianapublicmedia.org/eartheats/">Earth Eats</a>, that was right around the beginning of the resurgence of the local food movement, the modern day farm-to-table kind of idea. We started a podcast and blog that was local food focused, which was one of the first in that space and it blew up too. By the time I left, this dinky station was among the top ten public radio websites nationally.</p><p class="question"><strong>What brought you to Columbus?</strong></p><p>I moved here to do similar work at <a href="http://wosu.org/">WOSU</a>, but it wound up not being a good fit, so I only stayed a year. I helped launch a web presence for their classical music station, which went pretty well. It was culturally hard because I wanted to move a little faster, build a team, be a little more aggressive. It just wasn’t where they were yet, but I do think they’re doing better now.</p><p>I then worked for just about year in consulting, mostly with companies in higher education, healthcare, and financial services. I did social strategy, analytics, and research. It was interesting, but I missed working in news and the nonprofit world, so I ended up starting <a href="http://mediatoybox.com/">my own firm</a>.</p><p>INN was actually a client of mine and after a while it turned into a full time job, which is how I got to where I am now. I still do a little bit of freelance work, but not much. It trailed way off because my focus is now solely on building a team and products to support nonprofit news at INN.</p><p>So it’s been been kind of a weird path.</p><p class="question"><strong>You are probably better for it, though.</strong></p><p>I am super grateful to have had the diversity of experience, even for those really hard years during my undergrad where I was juggling all of the math, science, and music. If I had only been a music major, I would never have taken that amount of math and chemistry. Having that research experience was really beneficial for me because it made me apply the scientific method to my decision making process, which I use and am grateful for today.</p><p class="question"><strong>Tell me about your hobbies. The ones I know about are gardening, cycling, and small Ohio towns.</strong></p><p>Food is a big thing for me, which began when I started editing that food podcast. I always enjoyed cooking, but didn’t really get that much into it. It’s amazing what covering food policy will do for how you eat. It’s around that time that I became a vegetarian. I now grow, can, and cook a lot of my own food. At my house I ripped out the entire backyard and built raised beds, and am now a fairly serious gardener. In the summertime I spend a lot of time on that, which I enjoy because it’s an opportunity to be away from the screen. The more time I spend in front of a screen the more time I like to spend doing things that feel more tangible.</p><div class="media--left media--1-4 media--min-200"><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/aschweigert/10128224256/in/set-72157637789728673" class="media-image--link"><picture><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-photo-pleasantville-ohio-480by345-fe8300.jpg" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-photo-pleasantville-ohio-320by230-fe8300.jpg"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-photo-pleasantville-ohio-480by345-fe8300.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-photo-pleasantville-ohio-320by230-fe8300.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-photo-pleasantville-ohio-719by516-fe8300.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-photo-pleasantville-ohio-479by344-fe8300.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/02-adam-schweigert-photo-pleasantville-ohio-320by230-fe8300.jpg" alt="Photo from Pleasantville, Ohio" itemprop="contentURL" ></picture></a><div class="media-caption">A photo from Pleasantville, Ohio</a>.</div></div><p>Photography has been a hobby of mine for a long time. I am also a pretty serious runner, but lately I’ve been doing more cycling. The cycling and photography are the two hobbies that go into my <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/aschweigert/collections/72157632128870392/">small towns project</a>. I was born in Akron and have lived in Ohio most of my life, but I realized that I have seen almost none of it since I have just driven the highways instead of seeing the smaller towns.</p><p>So as a way of getting out more and doing more photography, I go on a bike trip almost every weekend. I usually ride 50 or 60 miles and I try to find at least a few small towns, which I take photos of. I would like to eventually turn these photos into a book. For me, it’s about experiencing the diversity of the state at a human scale and photographing the characteristic architecture of small town Ohio. A lot of small towns have deteriorated as people leave, so I want to capture some of that architecture before it disappears. It’s an ongoing project and there are something like 280 small towns in Ohio…</p><p class="question"><strong>…Are you going to make it to them all?</strong></p><p>[Laughing] I don’t know if I will make it to all of them. I have been to about 50 or 60, so we will see how far I will get. Maybe next summer I will do more of a focused project and do a Kickstarter to go and reshoot some of it. Right now I just pick a spot and then ride all of these back roads to hit the towns along the way. There isn’t much of a plan to it, but maybe I will be more methodical about it next summer.</p><p>Over the last year music has become a hobby again, which is my first time back to it since I got burned out on it during grad school. I have been learning banjo, which is completely different, but equally challenging and a lot of fun. I don’t play in a band or anything yet, it’s more of a personal hobby.</p><p>What else? I usually get on a weird kick where I become randomly interested in something and will then need to know everything that exists about it. That covers a lot of it.</p><br><hr><p>You’ve just read about <strong><a href="http://webworke.rs/adam-schweigert/">Adam Schweigert</a></strong> on <strong><a href="http://webworke.rs/">Webworke.rs</a></strong>, a website about folks who make websites in Columbus, OH.</p><p>For updates, follow us on <strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/Webworkers614">Facebook</a></strong>, <strong><a href="https://plus.google.com/+Webworkers614/">Google+</a></strong>, <strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/webworkers">LinkedIn</a></strong>, <strong><a href="http://Webworkers614.tumblr.com">Tumblr</a></strong>, and <strong><a href="http://twitter.com/Webworkers614">Twitter</a></strong>.</p>
 ]]></content></entry><entry><title type="text">Matthew Russo</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://webworke.rs/matthew-russo/" /><id>http://webworke.rs/matthew-russo</id><published>2014-07-25T10:12:00-04:00</published><updated>2014-07-25T10:12:00-04:00</updated><category term="design" label="Design"/><category term="digital-strategy" label="Digital Strategy"/><category term="marketing" label="Marketing"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ Matthew Russo works with systems, technology, marketing and design as Vice President of Design &amp; Product Development at <a href="http://30lines.com/">30 Lines</a>. He’s also the founder of <a href="http://www.blastbrand.com/">Blast Brand</a> and <a href="http://socialautoleads.com/">Social Auto Leads</a>, a co-founder of <a href="http://chatterjet.com/">ChatterJet</a>, and the author of <a href="http://systemsforgrowth.com/">Systems for Growth</a>, a blog that helps business owners stop wasting time and start making impact. ]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p class="lede"><span class="lede-location">Short North Cup o' Joe &mdash;</span> Matthew Russo works with systems, technology, marketing and design as Vice President of Design &amp; Product Development at <a href="http://30lines.com/">30 Lines</a>. He’s also the founder of <a href="http://www.blastbrand.com/">Blast Brand</a> and <a href="http://socialautoleads.com/">Social Auto Leads</a>, a co-founder of <a href="http://chatterjet.com/">ChatterJet</a>, and the author of <a href="http://systemsforgrowth.com/">Systems for Growth</a>, a blog that helps business owners stop wasting time and start making impact.</p><p class="question"><strong>Who are you and what do you do?</strong></p><p>My name is Matthew Russo and while I don’t have an official title, I work in the digital space, so anything that touches a website or the internet in general. It could be anything from building the information architecture of a website, to designing the user interfaces, to linking them up to other systems, such as email and social media. Everything in that world.</p><div class="media--right media--1-2 media--min-150"><picture><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-at-desk-800by513-a3a38f.jpg" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-at-desk-767by492-a3a38f.jpg"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-at-desk-480by308-a3a38f.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-at-desk-320by205-a3a38f.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-at-desk-719by461-a3a38f.jpg" media="(max-width: 959px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 959px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-at-desk-479by307-a3a38f.jpg" media="(max-width: 959px)"><img srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-at-desk-767by492-a3a38f.jpg" alt="Photo of Matthew Russo at his desk in the 30 Lines office" ></picture><div class="media-caption">Matthew Russo at his desk in the <a href="http://30lines.com/" class="media-link">30 Lines</a> office.</div></div><p class="question"><strong>How did you get into this line of work?</strong></p><p>It was a roundabout kind of way. I went to school at the University of Cincinnati and studied Industrial Design, which is anything from shoes to furniture to cars; really it’s anything that’s three dimensional. I wanted to go to school for graphic design, because I was always interested in the way things look from an aesthetic view. But I found my way into industrial and that really opened my eyes to how things work. There are a lot of processes behind how you manufacture a table or a car tire, which are obviously very different things.</p><p>While I was in school I wanted to become a car designer, which led to a studio with Dodge. Those guys came down from Detroit to look at our work and critique it, which was good for us because we were getting input from the best designers in the world, and it was good for them because they were basically recruiting the top talent to go work for them once we graduated. But right before I graduated I decided that I didn’t want to do that for the rest of my life.</p><p>As I fell away from that, I then ended up designing indoor water parks across the country. I don’t know if you remember the craze about six or seven years ago when they were popping up all over the place. Developers were attaching them to hotels, just like the Fort Rapids that’s off I-70. Architects would go in and build these big structures and our company (<a href="http://www.theming.net/">General Theming Contractor</a>, on the East Side of Columbus), would go in and theme out the inside of them.</p><p>Along that same time I was doing more and more stuff online. I was heading up the marketing for a local nonprofit (<a href="https://www.snapcolumbus.org/">SNAP! Performance Productions</a>), working to help them generate buzz, tinkering around on websites, and one thing led to another. I jumped on Twitter in 2008, which is where I saw the job opening for <a href="http://www.bulx.com/">BULX.com</a>, a high end home improvement flash sale site. I created an online video for part of my application and they really liked it.</p><div class="media--left media--1-4 media--min-150"><a href="http://bulx.com/" class="media-image--link"><picture><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-bulx-480by374-db6e0e.jpg" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-bulx-320by249-db6e0e.jpg"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-bulx-480by374-db6e0e.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-bulx-320by249-db6e0e.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-bulx-719by560-db6e0e.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-bulx-479by373-db6e0e.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-bulx-320by249-db6e0e.jpg" alt="Screenshot of Bulx.com" itemprop="contentURL" ></picture></a><div class="media-caption">The website for <a href="http://bulx.com/" class="media-link">Bulx.com</a>.</div></div><p>Soon after, I joined BULX.com as the Director of Online Marketing and Social Media. It was a start-up out of <a href="http://www.techcolumbus.org/">Tech Columbus</a>, and there were only four of us in there who were in charge of the marketing and technology side. We had a partner in Chicago who was in charge of all the products. Everyday we’d have high end sinks, faucets, toilets, and rugs to sell for the home. We would get them at really deep discounts and they would be on sale anywhere from 40-80% off. Our team in Columbus was in charge of acquiring new members, loading all of the product into the site, and sending out the daily email for the sale.</p><p>We pretty quickly saw that we were acquiring customers much faster than our partner in Chicago was acquiring products, so our runway got really short, really quickly. We grew from zero members to over twenty thousand over the course of eight and a half months and generated hundreds of thousands of dollars of revenue. We had this base of people expecting emails every day, but we didn’t always have something to sell them.</p><p class="question"><strong>That must have been an unexpected problem, since no one ever plans for too many customers.</strong></p><p>Right, exactly. BULX.com was eventually sold to a liquidator in New York, so they have access to a nearly unlimited supply of product to sell. I don't know what their growth strategy looks like today, but at the time it was a perfect fit. They had lots of product to move and they wanted a new audience for it, and we had a big audience we needed product for - so the acquisition made a lot of sense.</p><p class="question"><strong>My first introduction to your work was the fundraising campaign that you did for your friend Lindsay. Not only was the cause worthwhile, but the messaging was compelling. It had depth that really pulled me into it. I’m sure I wasn’t the only one. Previous to that, had you undertaken anything of that scope?</strong></p><p>It’s funny that you mention scope because there was never any plan to make it some massive initiative that gained national recognition. Eventually, it turned into something much bigger than I expected and was a little more work, but that was never the goal.</p><p>The <a href="http://forlindsay.com/">entire campaign</a> was literally an idea I came up with for a friend where I thought, “This is a story that people need to hear” and “I think I can make a difference in her life.”</p><div class="media--right media--1-2 media--min-150"><div class="FlexEmbed"><div class="FlexEmbed-ratio FlexEmbed-ratio--16by9"></div><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/48981619?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0" class="FlexEmbed-content" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></div><div class="media-caption">Video courtesy of <a href="http://beonscene.com/" class="media-link">OnScene Productions</a>.</div></div><p>Lindsay was a longtime friend who I was introduced to after moving back from Cincinnati. When she was diagnosed with Stage 3 breast cancer, it totally blindsided her, her husband, and all of their family because she was so young (only 27 at the time), active, and didn’t have any family history of the disease.</p><p>After battling cancer for nearly two years, she and her husband Tony decided they had waited long enough to start their family. They had been proactive about it before Lindsay started all the cancer treatments, but when it came time to start, the only option they had was to go through a surrogate. Because that process is so expensive (anywhere from $60,000 - $80,000, without using a surrogacy agency), I felt I could do something to help. I thought, “If money is the only thing standing between this awesome couple, who has already gone through so much, and their dream of having a family, there’s got to be something I can do to help them.”</p><p>Over the course of those four months leading up to the full marathon I ran in her honor, we ended up raising almost $28,000. And their son just had his first birthday party last month, which is awesome.</p><p>It’s interesting because some of the nonprofit work that I had been doing tied into the messaging and how I thought through the story I wanted to tell for Lindsay. But, how can you make it compelling enough for other people to care?</p><div class="media--left media--1-4 media--min-150"><picture><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-for-lindsay-instagram-480by480-4ae1d0.jpg" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-for-lindsay-instagram-320by320-4ae1d0.jpg"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-for-lindsay-instagram-480by480-4ae1d0.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-for-lindsay-instagram-320by320-4ae1d0.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-for-lindsay-instagram-612by612-4ae1d0.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-for-lindsay-instagram-479by479-4ae1d0.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-for-lindsay-instagram-320by320-4ae1d0.jpg" alt="Photo of Matthew Russo after running For Lindsay" ></picture><div class="media-caption">Post marathon Instagram.</div></div><p>At the time I was training for a half marathon and I thought, “Yeah, I think I can do the full marathon.” Literally, while I was out on a training run, I had the idea to make a website for her and then turn this into something bigger. I met with the couple to tell them about my idea, and they loved it.</p><p>I looped in Eric Leslie from <a href="http://beonscene.com/">OnScene Productions</a>, who put together the video, which really was the focal point of the whole thing. It helped tell their story in a beautiful way and inspiring way.</p><p>It was my job to help get the word out, to start with the friends and family and let it spread from there. It was cool to literally see the story spread once people watched the video. Eventually, 69% percent of all the website traffic came from social media. People came to the site, saw the video, and were then compelled to donate to the cause and share it with their connections.</p><p class="question clear"><strong>That is the dream for a lot of people who manage brands.</strong></p><p>I think it’s something a lot of brands take for granted, or maybe don’t understand. If you build something from scratch and just expect people to show up, it’s probably not going to happen, even if it’s really well optimized for search.</p><p>You need that base of early adopters to get the ball rolling, so I started with friends and family.</p><p>It was perfect; a lot of my friends and family already knew Lindsay so it was the perfect tie to get them to spread the message. So I started local, close to home and let is spread from there. We had some tactics to build on that experience, too. Anyone who donated was added to an email list so we could keep them updated with the progress. We then used that base of people to help get the word out about other initiatives.</p><p>Do you remember what happened with Giuliana Rancic? We sent out a group email to everyone who already donated and asked, “Hey, do you want to help us reach out to this A-list celebrity?” And overwhelmingly people responded, “Hell yeah, I already donated. I’d like to help further this along.”</p><p>So I created a pre-populated tweet (using <a href="http://clicktotweet.com/">ClickToTweet.com</a>) that everyone tweeted at her. Guilianna got 20 or so of the same tweets at 8 in the morning, and by 9AM she then sent out <a href="https://twitter.com/GiulianaRancic/status/257845610198212608">an awesome tweet</a> and a link to her then 800,000 followers on Twitter, and that day blew up for the campaign.</p><blockquote class="quote quote-full"><p class="quote-text">Didn&#39;t expect tears at 9 am but this beautiful story is worth it. I&#39;m pulling &amp; praying 4 u Lindsay! Xo <a href="http://t.co/95AyjKAE">http://t.co/95AyjKAE</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ForLindsay?src=hash">#ForLindsay</a></p><cite class="citation-small">Giuliana Rancic (<a href="https://twitter.com/GiulianaRancic/" class="citation-small--link">@GiulianaRancic</a>)</cite></blockquote><p>There’s an interesting learning point to this. Her tweet sent 7,000 visitors to the site that day, at a time when we only had 6,500 hundred visitors leading up to that day. Those visitors (and I’m using air-quotes) “only” donated twelve or fifteen hundred dollars that day - which is awesome and we were really grateful for - but proportionally they should have donated much more based on how much people had been donating up to that point.</p><p>Again, that is a testament to people who are close to your message versus complete strangers. Everybody thinks that because it’s online and because it’s spread worldwide means the money is going to come pouring in. It’s actually easier to go through close friends and family than to spread the message to everybody and assume that it’s all going to come flowing in.</p><p class="question"><strong>Is Lindsay cancer free?</strong></p><p>She’s not. She’s still battling it every day. Her breast cancer spread to her back. For a while, they had it pretty well contained but she is battling through some pretty tough stuff again. She is so strong and has been kicking its ass for the past 5 years. If anyone can beat it for good, it’s her.</p><p>In the meantime, they are living their lives and I feel like I did my part to help contribute what I could. They are awesome people. I have no doubt they are going to get through it, but it is still a challenge. It’s a daily struggle for sure.</p><p class="question"><strong>Good luck to her and her family through this still trying experience.</strong></p><p class="question"><strong>Was Blast Brand your first solo foray into digital strategy and marketing?</strong></p><p>Yes, it was. When BULX.com was in the process of being acquired, I had to figure out what I wanted to do next. I knew it wasn’t going to be a nine to five at some big company, so I started my own company, which is <a href="http://www.blastbrand.com/">Blast Brand</a>.</p><div class="media--right media--1-4 media--min-150"><a href="http://blastbrand.com/" class="media-image--link"><picture><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-blast-brand-480by374-5a0313.jpg" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-blast-brand-320by249-5a0313.jpg"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-blast-brand-480by374-5a0313.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-blast-brand-320by249-5a0313.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-blast-brand-719by560-5a0313.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-blast-brand-479by373-5a0313.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-blast-brand-320by249-5a0313.jpg" alt="Screenshot of BlastBrand.com" itemprop="contentURL" ></picture></a><div class="media-caption">The website for <a href="http://blastbrand.com/" class="media-link">BlastBrand.com</a>.</div></div><p>At the same time I started working with Mike Whaling over at <a href="http://30lines.com/">30 Lines</a>. It was just him when we started working together. I had a handful of clients that I acquired through Blast Brand, and he was looking for help because he had clients of his own that he was looking to grow. We have been working in tandem since. I have always maintained my clients, but I am now spending the majority of my time at 30 Lines. We are up to a team of eight full-time people, so that has grown significantly.</p><p>It’s interesting because there’s obviously a lot of overlap with what we provide and how we approach things, but our audiences are very different. Mike grew out of the multi-family apartment industry, so we build a lot of websites and do a lot of email marketing and social media for apartment communities in Columbus, Chicago, Florida, California, and up and down the East Coast. That is where I focus a lot of my time with him.</p><div class="media--left media--1-4 media--min-150"><a href="http://30lines.com/" class="media-image--link"><picture><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-30-lines-480by374-e0cfe0.jpg" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-30-lines-320by249-e0cfe0.jpg"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-30-lines-480by374-e0cfe0.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-30-lines-320by249-e0cfe0.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-30-lines-719by560-e0cfe0.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-30-lines-479by373-e0cfe0.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-30-lines-320by249-e0cfe0.jpg" alt="Screenshot of 30Lines.com" itemprop="contentURL" ></picture></a><div class="media-caption">The website for <a href="http://30lines.com/" class="media-link">30Lines.com</a>.</div></div><p>We are also working on a really cool project to integrate our front-end marketing sites (which we build with WordPress), to the real time data from multi-family apartment complexes. In the industry, a lot of websites are built by what are essentially accounting companies, who provide software to manage the rent and the people who are living within these communities.</p><p>They said, “Wow, we have all this data, so we should become marketing companies too.” As a result they have these divisions that sell websites to integrate with their accounting software, but they approach it like an accounting company. They don’t have the marketing chops or the digital awareness of how websites should work or what the best practices are on the web. Yes, they are functioning websites, but they’re only now working towards making responsive websites, which has been the standard for several years now.</p><p>We approach it from the other side: What are best practices online? How can we drive traffic to the site? How can we increase the number of people who are requesting more information or applying on those websites? How can we do some cool, fun stuff to keep the funnel filled for these apartment websites?</p><p>We are building the integration in-between these front-end marketing sites and where all the data lives for real-time availability, pricing, and other metrics. It’s a WordPress plugin and it’s going to be pretty cool.</p><p class="question"><strong>Do these accounting companies provide APIs?</strong></p><p>Some of them.</p><p class="question"><strong>Most of the websites I’ve seen for apartment complexes are terrible, so there’s obviously a market there to improve upon the model.</strong></p><p>Yes. There are a handful of those providers currently, and some of their websites and documentation are better than others. Recently, one of them has been changing their API and we actually found out about it before some of their employees did. The feeds on a couple of our websites broke, and when our client asked us, “What’s going on?” we said, “OK, we’ll call this provider and see what’s up.” We called and they said, “Oh yeah, looks like the API changed. I guess we are going to scramble to put some documentation together about the fixes you guys need to make.” So that’s a lot of fun.</p><p class="question"><strong>The joys of making websites that depend on third party data, right?</strong></p><p>Exactly. There’s a ton of information to parse through, so it’s part of the challenge and opportunity. We need to figure out what to display on the back-end for our clients, while also considering how that ties into the front-end experience for potential renters.</p><p class="question"><strong>Neat. Good luck!</strong></p><p>I’ll keep you posted. It’s a fun challenge.</p><p class="question"><strong>So you have a lot of projects [laughing]. Could you give me a quick rundown of each? You’ve got ChatterJet. You’ve got Systems for Growth. And you’ve got Social Auto Leads. Am I forgetting any?</strong><p>None of the top level stuff, no.</p><p class="question"><strong>How many burners do you have?</strong></p><p>For example, Bryce Thornton and I built <a href="http://chatterjet.com/">ChatterJet</a> after learning about the social media challenges that face small to medium-sized businesses. They kept telling me, “We know we should be doing social media, but we don’t know what the heck we should be doing. We also don’t know how to do it ourselves and we don’t have a big budget to pay for it.”</p><div class="media--right media--1-4 media--min-150"><a href="http://chatterjet.com/" class="media-image--link"><picture><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-chatterjet-480by374-d818da.jpg" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-chatterjet-320by249-d818da.jpg"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-chatterjet-480by374-d818da.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-chatterjet-320by249-d818da.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-chatterjet-719by560-d818da.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-chatterjet-479by373-d818da.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-chatterjet-320by249-d818da.jpg" alt="Screenshot of ChatterJet.com" itemprop="contentURL" ></picture></a><div class="media-caption">The website for <a href="http://chatterjet.com/" class="media-link">ChatterJet.com</a>.</div></div><p>So with those three hypotheses, I said to Bryce, “Is there a way to automate and deliver custom content to these small businesses on an ongoing basis? How can we do it in a way that makes some money, too?” We built ChatterJet under those assumptions, but there’s also some limitations that we didn’t realize until we got into it.</p><p>We initially thought that it would be perfect for any small business, no matter what they do, but pretty quickly we learned that if you are a dry cleaner, social media probably isn’t not a great fit. This ties back to the messaging from the For Lindsay campaign. Who is really going to talk about dry cleaning? Who is doing the messaging behind that? Who’s really getting excited that their shirts are being well pressed? It’s more of a utility.</p><p>The other big piece is that the price point is so low that it doesn’t necessarily justify the time and money was being spent on social media for businesses like that. We would have dry cleaners sign up and they would say, “There aren’t a lot of people talking about dry cleaning on social media right now. Nobody is sharing our stuff, and it doesn’t make sense for us to just be posting stuff,” which I absolutely agree with.</p><div class="media--left media--1-4 media--min-150"><a href="http://socialautoleads.com/" class="media-image--link"><picture><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-social-auto-leads-480by374-a07ce5.jpg" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-social-auto-leads-320by249-a07ce5.jpg"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-social-auto-leads-480by374-a07ce5.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-social-auto-leads-320by249-a07ce5.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-social-auto-leads-719by560-a07ce5.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-social-auto-leads-479by373-a07ce5.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-social-auto-leads-320by249-a07ce5.jpg" alt="Screenshot of SocialAutoLeads.com" itemprop="contentURL" ></picture></a><div class="media-caption">The website for <a href="http://socialautoleads.com/" class="media-link">SocialAutoLeads.com</a>.</div></div><p>Some of the other lessons I learned from ChatterJet led me to <a href="http://socialautoleads.com/">Social Auto Leads</a>. If you can find products or services that people love talking about, that they are emotional about, and that have a high enough price point to justify the time and energy being spent on social media, then it makes sense to focus on that, which is what we did with Social Auto Leads.</p><p>Next, we looked at all the social media profiles for dealerships across the country and we realized that most of them are filled with horrible, awful stuff that nobody interacts with.</p><p>From a marketing checklist standpoint they are on Facebook, they are on Twitter, they are on Pinterest; but from a customer’s standpoint nobody is interacting with them. We said, “We can do this better,” so we started this as a service for auto groups and told them, “Hey, there is already a group of people online who are talking about their cars. We think we can start conversations with those people near your dealership. We think we can send you traffic and leads if it’s done right. So what do you say?”</p><p>So now we have clients in Columbus and Indianapolis. We are in talks with groups in New York and California, which is great, so the potential is there.</p><p>For the groups we’ve been working with over the last few months, we’ve already hit really great goals and not just on the impressions side, either. Everybody likes to see big, flashy numbers. For example, we generated 130,000 brand impressions on Twitter over the last three months for our local client alone.</p><p>But for me, it ultimately comes back to how many people are we sending through your dealership’s doors? How much traffic are we sending to your website? Those are the two focal points, especially on the website side, which is the focal point of your online presence. If we can do those two things everything else falls into place. Gaining followers is great, but that shouldn’t be the goal. Impressions shouldn’t be the goal and “Likes” shouldn’t be the goal, either. As we like to say, “Likes don’t sell cars. We do.”</p><p>We have been thinking about some cool opportunities to build for Social Auto Leads. There is an opportunity to take that model and expand it to other industries, too.</p><p class="question"><strong>What are your thoughts about the strengths and weaknesses of most brands with regards to their digital strategy?</strong></p><p>A lot of companies don’t know who their audience is, or who they are going after, or what they’re trying to achieve. They’re just reacting - looking at what everyone else is doing without understanding how it all works or ties together - and then launching things and expecting big results.</p><blockquote class="quote quote-small media--right media--1-4 media--min-200"><p class="quote-text">The code and the design is the easy part now. The challenge is finding an audience that actually cares and is willing to pay for your product because it delivers value to their organization.</p></blockquote><p>Especially with newer companies or start-ups, they thrash around and try to figure out what their product market fit is. So they spend a lot of time spinning their wheels and mistakenly thinking that “We just need to produce, to ship, and get our product out the door.” If they had a better understanding of who their client or prospective customer is and spent time talking to them to figure out what their challenges are, they would then have an easier time getting that product to the market.</p><p>There’s a ton of research about when it’s time to scale and when it’s time to put your head down and roll the product out, in the start-up space specifically. I won’t go into that, but if they spent more time talking to people, instead of putting their head down coding for a year because that is not what it’s about. The code and the design is the easy part now. The challenge is finding an audience that actually cares and is willing to pay for your product because it delivers value to their organization.</p><p>Telling your story in a compelling way, so that people are more willing to share it. I think that is the most interesting part to me right now. It’s not a problem with all brands, but a lot of brands need help. It such a competition right now to differentiate. We fight that, too. Not that we are struggling to find work, it’s the total opposite right now. But when there are a lot of people in town and across the country who have similar skill sets, you need to be very clear about what makes you different and the value you provide.</p><p class="question"><strong>What are your Systems for Growth. Are there systems in your life, in your career?</strong></p><p><a href="http://systemsforgrowth.com/">Systems for Growth</a> is my dumping ground for everything I’ve got going on in my head. I stumbled upon systems thinking a couple years ago. The basic premise is how do you piece everything together from a bigger picture standpoint, instead of just looking at individual elements. It’s how we approach our online presence, as well.</p><div class="media--left media--1-4 media--min-150"><a href="http://systemsforgrowth.com/" class="media-image--link"><picture><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-systems-for-growth-480by374-d8f68d.jpg" media="(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-systems-for-growth-320by249-d8f68d.jpg"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-systems-for-growth-480by374-d8f68d.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 320px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-systems-for-growth-320by249-d8f68d.jpg" media="(max-width: 320px)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-systems-for-growth-719by560-d8f68d.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (max-width: 479px) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)"><source srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-systems-for-growth-479by373-d8f68d.jpg" media="(max-width: 479px)"><img srcset="/generated/01-matthew-russo-screenshot-systems-for-growth-320by249-d8f68d.jpg" alt="Screenshot of SystemsForGrowth.com" itemprop="contentURL" ></picture></a><div class="media-caption">The website for <a href="http://systemsforgrowth.com/" class="media-link">SystemsForGrowth.com</a>.</div></div><p>For example, clients often come to us and say, “Hey, we want help with our social media.” We look at their overall presence and we respond, “Actually, your website is a train wreck and you don’t even have an email service provider set up. There are all these other ideas you could be working on. Let’s table the social media and take care of some bigger picture items before spending time and money on things that aren’t going to move the needle.”</p><p>Systems for Growth is my personal blog where I put my thoughts about how to approach, not only online systems, but eventually time management and financial systems as well. It’s my playground to dump my thoughts and experiment with this way of thinking.</p><p>I recently presented some of my thoughts from the blog at the Ohio Growth Summit in a session called “<a href='http://systemsforgrowth.com/four-pillars-business-growth/'>Why Building Bridges is Better Than Building Islands</a>”. The blog isn’t really something I really have to do on top of everything else, since it ties into everything I’m working on already. As a result, it gives me a place to collect my thoughts and share them with others.</p><p class="question"><strong>Speaking of family, you and your wife have a daughter?</strong></p><p>Yes.</p><p class="question"><strong>I’m sure your lives have changed in the past year. How do you manage work and life balance?</strong></p><p>Yes, it has. It has made me aware of how I spend my time at home and made me better at drawing borders between when I should be working and when I shouldn’t. It is very easy for us in the online world to think, “Hey, I’ve got a laptop and a connection, so I could be working right now.”</p><p>There's obviously value in disconnecting and spending time with family, old friends, and new connections. That has been the biggest change. When I get home, I am at home until my daughter goes to bed at least. Then, if I can put my head down for an hour or two at night, that’s fine. If I’m with her or my wife, that is what I’m focusing on.</p><p class="question"><strong>What is your typical work day? Is there a typical work day?</strong></p><p>Yeah, I am more of a morning person now that I have a daughter who wakes up around 6:15 AM. So coming to coffee wasn't so bad this morning, which is great.</p><p>My day typically starts with spending time with my family for an hour or so. Then, I get ready and come into the office, where I’ll write for a bit, either for Systems for Growth or some of the other places I contribute, such as my small column for <a href="http://www.themetropreneur.com/columbus/category/features/systems-for-growth/">The Metropreneur</a>. Then, I jump into email and see if there’s anything urgent and compare it to what’s on the agenda for the day. I figure out all the stuff that I need to get done this week. Then I divvy up and prioritize my work for the rest of the day. In the evening, I go home and spend some time with my family. If there’s any lingering stuff or any planning for the next day or the remainder of the week, I do that.</p><p class="question"><strong>Any hobbies when you have some free time?</strong></p><p>[Laughing] I have free time.</p><p class="question"><strong>Do you still run?</strong></p><p>Yes, I do. I’m currently training for the BTN Big 10K in Chicago, which is fun. Awhile back I wrote an article about how you can <a href="http://www.themetropreneur.com/columbus/create-time-life/">create more time in your life</a> with the word “and”. I’ve been thinking a lot about how you can do two things at once or three things at once. It’s not so much a multi-tasking concept, as much as it’s, “What things can I do that I value in life that pair well together?”</p><p>One of the things that I like to do is run, right? So how can I bring my family into that? Recently, I’ve been training by pushing my daughter in her running stroller (which she loves), and I’ve got a goal to run a number of races across the country. But instead of travelling to these races by myself, why not bring my family with me so we get to spend time together? I get to achieve some individual goals, spend quality time with my family, and see some new cities in the meantime.</p><p>For example, I ran the Nashville Half Maration in April. We have the Chicago race coming up in a few weeks. We also get to spend time with friends. We went down to Nashville with my brother and his girlfriend. When we go to Chicago we’ll spend some time with some friends from high school. It’s nice to see the country, do some fun stuff, and eat some good food too.</p><p class="question"><strong>I just recently went to Nashville this past spring and I really enjoyed it.</strong></p><p>Had you been there before?</p><p class="question"><strong>No, I had not. Living in Columbus, it’s far enough away, but it’s still approachable. You don’t need to buy a plane ticket, plus it doesn’t break the bank. It’s the same thing with Chicago.</strong></p><p>My wife and I have a general rule. Every year for our anniversary, we go somewhere new. We’ve been to Niagara Falls and Washington D.C. We actually did Detroit last year, which is only a three hour drive from Columbus, but we’d never been there. It was awesome. We have a rule to check out as much stuff close by. We haven’t been to Indianapolis, even though it’s right across the border, so we are going to do that soon. There’s so much opportunity nearby that we take for granted. People have these big aspirations like “I need to go to Europe. And I need to go to Southeast Asia.” I’m like, “Why don’t you drive six hours and go see St. Louis?”</p><p class="question"><strong>Yeah, you may not even know your own country.</strong></p><p>Yeah for sure.</p><p class="question"><strong>Do you have any clients that you are really excited about?</strong></p><p>They are all interesting in their own regard. It’s less about individual clients and more about determining if what they’re trying to achieve is interesting and worth our time.</p><p>It’s also about figuring out what their digital presence can and should look like. You need to have a website. You need to be doing email. I like to to take the approach of: this is your situation, this is the story you want to tell, these are your goals, this is the audience you are trying to reach - let’s figure out which levers to pull that are going to get you the most impact or bang for your buck.</p><p>Should you be doing everything online? Probably, eventually. To me it usually doesn’t make sense to set all these different platforms up, and then press go, just to see it wither away because you don’t have the resources to get it where it needs to be. Why don’t we start with the website and run a Twitter campaign or do some social listening to validate you ideas? Once that’s working, what can we add on next so that it’s building on itself and you aren’t killing yourself in the process. Customizing that approach for each client is what’s most interesting for me.</p><blockquote class="quote quote-full"><p class="quote-text">Today, it’s teaming up with people who have good stories to tell and who want to make an impact on the world is more interesting to me than someone coming to me with some money and saying, “We have this budget. Can you build something for us?”</p></blockquote><p>I am getting more selective on the types of projects I work on. When you are just starting out you take anything. The quantity breeds quality kind of stuff. Today, it’s teaming up with people who have good stories to tell and who want to make an impact on the world is more interesting to me than someone coming to me with some money and saying, “We have this budget. Can you build something for us?” Yes, we can build that for you, but what is it going to do in the long term? That is the question I keep in the back of my head.</p><p class="question"><strong>What is next for you personally, professionally? For Blast Brand or 30 Lines?</strong></p><p>My goal is always to keep growing, both on the personal level and business level. It comes back on the business side to making an impact. What can we do at scale so that we aren’t all over the place all the time? We fight this a lot internally because a.), we know how to do it all now and we see how that puzzle fits together and b.) our clients want it all.</p><p>It’s the groupthink of clients hearing about things online, “Vine is the new cool thing. All the kids are on Snapchat. Why don't we do something over there?”</p><p>It’s really easy for us to say that sounds fun, so let’s go try that out, without thinking about how that impacts our work flow internally or our client’s bottom lines. But it’s our job to ask the tough questions like, “Why do you think that’ll work for your organization” and “What do you hope to achieve with it?”</p><p>That’s not to say that we don’t like experimenting or we don’t like trying new things. Certain things work because they are new. Now, let’s figure out how to make them work for a lot of people, so that we can spend time providing value in an efficient way, instead of spinning our wheels, trying everything all over the place, and not seeing much progress from that.</p><br><hr><p>You’ve just read about <strong><a href="http://webworke.rs/matthew-russo/">Matthew Russo</a></strong> on <strong><a href="http://webworke.rs/">Webworke.rs</a></strong>, a website about folks who make websites in Columbus, OH.</p><p>For updates, follow us on <strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/Webworkers614">Facebook</a></strong>, <strong><a href="https://plus.google.com/+Webworkers614/">Google+</a></strong>, <strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/webworkers">LinkedIn</a></strong>, <strong><a href="http://Webworkers614.tumblr.com">Tumblr</a></strong>, and <strong><a href="http://twitter.com/Webworkers614">Twitter</a></strong>.</p>
 ]]></content></entry></feed>
